{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Advanced Database Systems",
    "Term": "Prelims",
    "Title": "Advanced Database Concepts",
    "LastModified": "21 September 2024",
    "Authors": [
      "Elmer Felisilda"
    ],
    "References": [
      "01 01_Handout_1"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "It is an organized collection of structured information or data typically stored electronically in a computer system.",
      "answer": "Database",
      "choices": [
        "Database",
        "Database Management System (DBMS)",
        "Database Application",
        "Users"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This is usually controlled by a Database Management system (DBMS).",
      "answer": "Database",
      "choices": [
        "Database",
        "Database Management System (DBMS)",
        "Database Application",
        "Users"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "It is an interface between the database and its end-users or programs, allowing users to retrieve, update, and manage how the information is organized and optimized.",
      "answer": "Database Management System (DBMS)",
      "choices": [
        "Database",
        "Database Management System (DBMS)",
        "Database Application",
        "Users"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "It facilitates oversight and control of databases, enabling a variety of administrative operations such as performance monitoring, tuning, and backup and recovery.",
      "answer": "Database Management System (DBMS)",
      "choices": [
        "Database",
        "Database Management System (DBMS)",
        "Database Application",
        "Users"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "It is a set of 1 or more computer programs that serves as an intermediary between the user and the DBMS.",
      "answer": "Database Application",
      "choices": [
        "Database",
        "Database Management System (DBMS)",
        "Database Application",
        "Users"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "It reads or modify database data by sending database queries to the DBMS.",
      "answer": "Database Application",
      "choices": [
        "Database",
        "Database Management System (DBMS)",
        "Database Application",
        "Users"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "These are unsophisticated users who interact with the system by using predefined UIs, such as web and mobile applications.",
      "answer": "Naive users",
      "choices": [
        "Naive users",
        "Application programmers",
        "Sophisticated users",
        "Normie Users"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "These are computer professionals who write application programs.",
      "answer": "Application programmers",
      "choices": [
        "Naive users",
        "Application programmers",
        "Sophisticated users",
        "Normie Users"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "These interacts with the system without writing programs.",
      "answer": "Sophisticated users",
      "choices": [
        "Naive users",
        "Application programmers",
        "Sophisticated users",
        "Normie Users"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "These form requests using a database query language.",
      "answer": "Sophisticated users",
      "choices": [
        "Naive users",
        "Application programmers",
        "Sophisticated users",
        "Normie Users"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "It involves database design and construction on how the databases will operate and function within existing structures and location.",
      "answer": "Database System Architecture",
      "choices": [
        "Database System Architecture",
        "Database Design",
        "Database Architecture",
        "Database"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of database system involves a database that supports data located at a single site.",
      "answer": "Centralized Database System",
      "choices": [
        "Centralized Database System",
        "Distributed Database System",
        "Advanced Database System",
        "Singular Database System"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of database system involves a collection of multiple interconnected databases, spread physically across various locations.",
      "answer": "Distributed Database System",
      "choices": [
        "Centralized Database System",
        "Distributed Database System",
        "Advanced Database System",
        "Singular Database System"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of data structure is stored in relational databases and uses a predefined and expected format or schema.",
      "answer": "Structured Data",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Data",
        "Unstructured Data",
        "Semi-structured Data",
        "Data"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of data structure in a DBMS exists in its original or raw state that can come in all shapes and sizes.",
      "answer": "Unstructured Data",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Data",
        "Unstructured Data",
        "Semi-structured Data",
        "Data"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of data structure in a DBMS involves individual data items of the same type may have different sets of attributes and contains semantic tags and there is no pre-defined schema.",
      "answer": "Semi-structured Data",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Data",
        "Unstructured Data",
        "Semi-structured Data",
        "Data"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of DBMS is a computer language for storing, manipulating, and retrieving data stored in a relational database.",
      "answer": "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "NewSQL",
        "Object-Oriented Database"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of DBMS is a new generation of DBMS that is not based on the traditional relational database model and has been developed to address the challenges represented by Big Data.",
      "answer": "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "NewSQL",
        "Object-Oriented Database"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of DBMS features a dynamic schema for unstructured data and the data can be stored in different ways.",
      "answer": "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "NewSQL",
        "Object-Oriented Database"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of DBMS allows you to create documents without first having to carefully plan and defined their structure.",
      "answer": "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "NewSQL",
        "Object-Oriented Database"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of DBMS incorporates and builds on the concepts and principles of SQL and NoSQL systems.",
      "answer": "NewSQL",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "NewSQL",
        "Object-Oriented Database"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of DBMS stores objects rather than data as individual relations.",
      "answer": "Object-Oriented Database",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "NewSQL",
        "Object-Oriented Database"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of DBMS uses OOP languages such as C++, Java, and C#.",
      "answer": "Object-Oriented Database",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "NewSQL",
        "Object-Oriented Database"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of DBMS is useful when you have a business need for high performance on complex data.",
      "answer": "Object-Oriented Database",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "NewSQL",
        "Object-Oriented Database"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of DBMS is designed to facilitate the exchange of structured documents.",
      "answer": "Extensible Markup Language (XML)",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "Extensible Markup Language (XML)",
        "Procedural Language SQL (PL-SQL)"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of DBMS simplifies data sharing between various systems because of its platform-independent nature.",
      "answer": "Extensible Markup Language (XML)",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "Extensible Markup Language (XML)",
        "Procedural Language SQL (PL-SQL)"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of DBMS is useful as long as your datasets stay relatively small.",
      "answer": "Extensible Markup Language (XML)",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "Extensible Markup Language (XML)",
        "Procedural Language SQL (PL-SQL)"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This SQL extension is a combination of SQL along with the procedural features of programming language.",
      "answer": "Procedural Language SQL (PL-SQL)",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "Extensible Markup Language (XML)",
        "Procedural Language SQL (PL-SQL)"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This SQL extension is developed by Oracle Corporation.",
      "answer": "Procedural Language SQL (PL-SQL)",
      "choices": [
        "Structured Query Language (SQL)",
        "Not only SQL (NoSQL)",
        "Extensible Markup Language (XML)",
        "Procedural Language SQL (PL-SQL)"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This SQL extension adds and declare variables, support transaction control, error and exception handling, and row processing to SQLs existing functions.",
      "answer": "Transact SQL (T-SQL)",
      "choices": [
        "Transact SQL (T-SQL)",
        "PostgreSQL",
        "MySQL",
        "SQLite"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This SQL extension is Microsoft and Sybaseâ€™s extension of SQL.",
      "answer": "Transact SQL (T-SQL)",
      "choices": [
        "Transact SQL (T-SQL)",
        "PostgreSQL",
        "MySQL",
        "SQLite"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This SQL extension is an open-source object-relational database system that uses and extends the SQL language.",
      "answer": "PostgreSQL",
      "choices": [
        "Transact SQL (T-SQL)",
        "PostgreSQL",
        "MySQL",
        "SQLite"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This SQL extension is an open-source relational DBMS developed and supported by Oracle.",
      "answer": "MySQL",
      "choices": [
        "Transact SQL (T-SQL)",
        "PostgreSQL",
        "MySQL",
        "SQLite"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This SQL extension is a relational DBMS contained in a C programming library.",
      "answer": "SQLite",
      "choices": [
        "Transact SQL (T-SQL)",
        "PostgreSQL",
        "MySQL",
        "SQLite"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement block defines a set of SQL statements that execute together.",
      "answer": "BEGIN/END",
      "choices": [
        "BEGIN/END",
        "DECLARE",
        "SET/SELECT",
        "CAST"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement block assigns a variable in an SQL server.",
      "answer": "DECLARE",
      "choices": [
        "BEGIN/END",
        "DECLARE",
        "SET/SELECT",
        "CAST"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement block require you to have your variable names start at \"@\".",
      "answer": "DECLARE",
      "choices": [
        "BEGIN/END",
        "DECLARE",
        "SET/SELECT",
        "CAST"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement block assigns values to a variable.",
      "answer": "SET/SELECT",
      "choices": [
        "BEGIN/END",
        "DECLARE",
        "SET/SELECT",
        "CAST"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement block converts an expression of one data type to another.",
      "answer": "CAST",
      "choices": [
        "BEGIN/END",
        "DECLARE",
        "SET/SELECT",
        "CAST"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement block prints a pre-defined message or value.",
      "answer": "PRINT",
      "choices": [
        "PRINT",
        "TRY/CATCH",
        "DECLARE",
        "SET/SELECT"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement block helps deal with any unexpected or exceptional situations that occur when a program/query is running.",
      "answer": "TRY/CATCH",
      "choices": [
        "PRINT",
        "TRY/CATCH",
        "DECLARE",
        "SET/SELECT"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement specifies a block of code to be executed, if the returning condition is true.",
      "answer": "IF-ELSE",
      "choices": [
        "IF-ELSE",
        "ELSE",
        "ELSE-IF",
        "WHILE"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement specifies a block of code to be executed, if the returning condition is false.",
      "answer": "ELSE",
      "choices": [
        "IF-ELSE",
        "ELSE",
        "ELSE-IF",
        "WHILE"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement specifies a new condition to test, if the previous returning condition is false.",
      "answer": "ELSE-IF",
      "choices": [
        "IF-ELSE",
        "ELSE",
        "ELSE-IF",
        "WHILE"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement loops through a block of code as long as a specified condition is true.",
      "answer": "WHILE",
      "choices": [
        "IF-ELSE",
        "ELSE",
        "ELSE-IF",
        "WHILE"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement is an extension of the IF-ELSE statement.",
      "answer": "CASE",
      "choices": [
        "CASE",
        "IF-ELSE",
        "ELSE-IF",
        "WHILE"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This T-SQL statement allows the user to apply multiple conditions to perform different sets of actions.",
      "answer": "CASE",
      "choices": [
        "CASE",
        "IF-ELSE",
        "ELSE-IF",
        "WHILE"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    }
  ]
}